专心点儿 Jonny
Let's stay focused, johnny.
你在看什么呢?
What are you looking at?
她是谁?
Who is she?
那是Cindy小姐 Zeke的新护工
That's miss cindy, zeke's new aide.
他原来的护工呢?
What happened to his old aide?
她结婚了
She got married.
好了 首先 你要把胶水涂在纸上
So, first, you want toabcrub the glue on the paper
什么形状都可以
in any shapes you like.
人们为什么要结婚?
Why do people get married?
因为他们爱对方
Because they love each other.
那你为什么不结婚?
Why aren't you married?
我还没找到我爱的人abc我把时间都用来爱你了
I haven't found the person I love yet,abcbecause I spend all of my time loving you.
那是不是说我们可以结婚?
Does that mean we can get married?
爱分为很多种 也有不同的表达方式
Well, love comes in many types, andabcthere's lots of it to go around.
噢 我的雪花完了
Oh, my snow is ruined.
怎么会呢
It's not ruined.
真漂亮
Oh, it's pretty.
你看 我喜欢这绿色
See, look, I like the green.
有谁见过绿色的雪?
Who ever heard of green snow?
奇幻的色彩
It's magical.
过来
Come here.
我帮你清理干净 好吗?
We'll get you cleaned up, okay?
没关系的
It's okay.
你没事吧?
Ooh,are you okay?
你不打算付钱?
You gonna pay for that?
既然是你请客
Nice of you to offer.
我多拿几块奶油干酪好了
Now I can actuallyabcget some cream cheese.
29岁的老师 教育特殊儿童 她--
29-year-old teacher-- she worksabcwith special needs children. She--
我喜欢你这一身
love what you're wearing.
和蓝色的文件夹交相辉映abc意味着这不是急诊室的病例
Brings out the blue of the case file,abcwhich means it's not from the E.R.
你来干什么?
So why are you here?
Cuddy医生不在
Because dr. Cuddy is not here.
她这阵子想多花时间在家照顾孩子
She's decided to spend some more timeabcat home with the baby for a while.
因此由我接替她的日常职责abc其中包括 看住你
I'm taking over some of he day-to-dayabcresponsibilities, like babysitting you.
有意思
Interesting.
你正值人生的大好年华
You have your whole life ahead of you.
Cuddy怎么忍心让你送死?
So why would cuddy wantabcyou to die so young?
她认为我曾经和你共事三年abc有经验看管你
She figured I'd spent three yearsabcworking for you. I was inoculated.
好哇 好玩
Good. Fun.
你试试看发淫威
You get to exercise your new found power.
我讨厌学生爬到老师头上abc我会在你底下兴风作浪
I squirm under your thumb, resentabcthe student becoming the teacher,
把你逼得无路可走 教你分清尊卑主次
and then push comes to shove, and we allabcget to realize what our real roles should be.
等着受死吧
Then you put out.
这正是我接受这个职位的目的
That's why I took the job.
29岁的特殊教育老师 大量咳血
29-year-old special ed. Teacherabccoughs up blood all over corky.
未见呼吸困难或体重减轻
No dyspnea, no weight loss.
你偷笑什么?
Why are you smirking?
想不到 我能活着看到abc你给Cameron打工的一天
Never thought I'see the day youabcwere taking orders from cameron.
- 医院由Cameron负责了?abc- 什么时候的事?
- Cameron's in charge?abc- When did that happen?
你会把她给灭了 对吧?
you're gonna destroy her, aren't you?
我只会做好本分
I am going to do my job.
如果我的本分包括在abc她抽屉塞烂苹果的话...
If that involves leavingabcher a rotting pulp...
Cameron要树立她的威信
cameron's gonna mark her territory.
她很可能会全力以赴 反过来把你灭了
She'll probablyabcover compensate and destroy you.
溃疡出血
Bleeding ulcer.
胃和肺的扫描没问题
Scope of the stomachabcand lungs were clean,
但她仍从肺部和胃部咳出血来
yet she continues to spit up bloodabcfrom both her stomach and lungs.
就是说她的血液本身有问题--
That means it's probably somethingabcwrong with the blood itself--
白血病 血管性血友病
leukemia, von willebrand's.
胸部肿瘤更符合abc侵蚀她的气管和食道--
Thoracic tumor is a better fit. Erodesabcinto her airway and esophagus--
你们两个能不能消停一会?
oh, will you two stop it already?
消停什么?
Stop what?
意见不合
Disagreeing.
那你说 我俩谁不应该发表意见?
Okay, which one of usabcshouldn't have an opinion?
这不是意见 这是烟幕
It's not an opinion.abcIt's a smoke screen.
Foreman提出了好主意在先abc你为表反对 硬抛出一个烂的
Toss out a lame idea, instead ofabcagreeing with foreman's better idea
因为你担心会让别人发现abc他勇敢地踏入了那片处女地
because you're worried that'll confirm thatabche's boldly gone where no man has gone before.
- 你和Foreman上床了?abc- 抱歉 咱没空聊这个
- You slept with foreman?abc- Sorry. You were busy.
别闹了 House
Drop it, house.
我们是在约会 话题到此结束
We're seeing eachabcother, end of discussion.
这跟其他人毫无关系
Anything else isn't relevant.
关系大了
It's extremely relevant.
显然 这妨碍了我们的判断
Apparently, it colors everything.
现在我搞不清楚abc你们提出不同意见
Now I have no idea if youabchave differing opinions
是真的意见向左 还是纯粹为了abc证明你们仍有独立思考的能力
because you have differing opinions or because you'reabcjust trying to prove that you can think for yourselves.
你为什么不能只凭意见abc本身来判断它的正误呢?
How about you just judge ourabcideas on their own merit?
你不会想我这么做的
Oh, you don't want me to do that.
去做个出血时间检测abc看看是不是血液问题
Go run a bleeding-time test, confirmabcour patient's blood is screwy.
然后你俩就可以接着abc就血液问题各执一词了
Then you can come back andabcpretend to disagree about why.
开始计时
Time zero.
厉害 你连手都没缩一下
I'm impressed. You didn't even flinch.
我在想开心的事
I just went to my happy place.
绝不能让House靠近她半步
We cannot let houseanywhereabcnear this woman.
什么开心的事?
Where is your happy place?
和我的学生在一起
My class, with them.
过了第一个记号位
passed the first mark.
你的工作很伟大
It's a great thing you do.
其实没有
Not really.
大部分孩子 独特的孩子--abc你给他们剪刀 他们拿起就会用
Most kids, typical children-- you handabcthem a pair of scissors, and they cut.
但Tony-- 他是脑瘫患儿abc我给他一把剪刀以后
Well, tony-- he's got C.P., Andabcwhen I gave him the scissors,
还要经历一个学习过程abc教他怎样把手指穿过把手
we went on a journey together, learningabcto get his fingers in those holes,
去握住剪刀的两侧 拿起纸张
to hold the scissorsabcapart, to hold the paper.
当他终于学会用剪刀时abc我们会高兴得留下眼泪
I mean, when he finally learned toabccut, we both just wept with joy.
当你见到我们上司时abc尽量别跟他多扯 好吗?
If you ever meet our boss,justabcyes or no answers, okay?
出血没有减缓 没有凝血迹象
It's not slowing up.abcNo sign of clotting.
那么说是我的血液有问题?
So there is somethingabcwrong with my blood?
别害怕 我们去检验是哪种凝血因子缺失abc然后--
Don't worry,we'll run some lab tests to findabcout which clotting factor is off and then--
我不害怕
I'm not worried.
你想的一定是件很开心的事
Must be one hell of a happy place.
她真漂亮
She's beautiful.
我知道 我很幸运
I know. I'm lucky.
没错
Absolutely.
她喜欢什么?
What's she like?
她才八星期大
She's eight weeks old.
你是指她的政治倾向呢 还是她的笑点?
Are you asking me aboutabcher politics or her sense of humor?
我表哥有个孩子
My cousin had a kid.
一生下来 他们就仿佛察觉了他所有喜好
They acted like they knew the thingabcfrom the time it was two minutes old.
我只是-- 想
I just--Iabcjust thought--
她会哭 会吃东西 会便便
she cries, she eats,and she poops.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我没有感觉
I don't feel anything.
你累了
You're tired.
我的睡眠时间没有减少abc她夜里睡得很好
I'm not sleep deprived. She sleeps fine.
显然我也没有产后抑郁问题
I'm obviously not hormonal.
我知道 我应该感到惊喜
I know I'm supposed to feel amazement.
感觉到对她的爱 但我...
I'm supposed to love her. I just...
什么也感觉不到
I don't feel anything at all.
对不起 也许我真的累了
Sorry. Maybe I am just tired.
谢谢你路过来看我 我没事
thank you for stopping by. I'm okay.
Lisa... 如果你...
Lisa... if you're...
我会喂她吃东西abc给她换尿布 照顾她
I am feeding her, I'm changingabcher,and I'm burping her.
做一切我应该做的事
I'm doing everything I'm supposed to do.
她会好好的
She will be okay.
回去上班吧
Please go back to work.
是血液本身导致abc但不是凝血蛋白的问题
it is the blood, but the clottingabcproteins aren't the problem.
是血小板 看起来像被咬过似的
It's her platelets, lookedabclike they had bite marks in them.
你们意见一致了?
So now you're agreeing?
要么是因为我揶揄你们而抱团abc要么是分手了 要么--
Either you folded because I gaveabcyou crap, or you broke up, or--
我们意见不合 你怪在我们的关系头上
we disagree,you blame our relationship.
我们达成一致 你还是怪在这上面
We agree, you blame our relationship.
- 发现问题出在哪了吗?abc- 发现了 你没有么?
- Don't you see a problem there?abc- Yes. Don't you?
可能是淋巴癌
could be lymphoma.
乳酸脱氢酶正常
Not with normal ldh.
特发性血小板减少性紫癜(I.T.P)abc符合症状 应该给她用甲氨蝶呤
I.T.P.Fits. We shouldabcstart her on methotrexate.
没错 去给她做全身放疗
Absolutely,and total body irradiation.
就凭出血时间不正常这一症状?
Because she failed a bleeding-time test?
全身放疗会使癌症恶化abc并毁掉她的消化系统
tbi will promote cancers,abckill her digestive tract.
但别忘了-- 阻止血液流入脑部
Don't forget--stop her fromabcbleeding into her brain.
这是一个不成熟 不顾后果abc而且可能使病人致死的疗法
It's premature, reckless,andabcpotentially lethal.
没错 某人有责任阻止我这种abc不顾后果且不负责任的行为
True. Must be somebody's job to stopabcme from being reckless and irresponsible.
但没人能阻止我不成熟
Nobody can stop me from being premature.
病人患有I.T.P
Got a patient with I.T.P.
要给她做全身放疗
Need to hit her with radiation.
我回头打给你
I'm gonna have to call you back.
- 用甲氨蝶呤abc- 好主意
- Methotrexate.abc- Good point.
但一旦血液流入她的脑部abc她自己也要接受特殊教育了
On the other hand, if she bleeds in her brain,abcshe's gonna need a special ed. Class of her own.
好吧
Fine.
- 真的?abc- 真的 你觉得合适就去做吧
- Really?abc- Yeah, if you think it's right, do it.
有人认为 你会使出霹雳手腕以建立威信
Some people thought you were gonnaabcbe brutal, marking your territory.
- 谁?abc- 谁也不是
- Who?abc- Nobody.
虽然我说他"谁也不是"abc不代表我有种族歧视
Just because I call himabcnobody doesn't make me a racist.
我不是在和你玩
I'm not gonna play games.
你向我提出申请 如果具有abc医学上的合理性 我会答应
If you come to me with a request andabcit makes medical sense,I'll say yes.
我需要口交
I need oral sex.
我很肯定abc生理的迫切性等同医学的合理性
I'm pretty sure biologicalabcimperative qualifies as medical sense.
我可以回电话了吗?
Can I return my phone call now?
我看不出有什么理由让你回
I don't really see howabcthat's gonna be possible.
甲氨蝶呤对病人不起作用abc出血时间也没有改善
patient won't respond to methotrexate.abcBleeding time hasn't improved.
你给我出了个难题abc我也给你出一个
You havea medical dilemmaabcfor me. I have one for you.
给我一个不做全身放疗的理由
I need a reason to notabcdototal body irradiation.
Cameron不是给你了吗?
Other than that cameron said you can'T.
她说我可以
She said I can.
那我们照做就是了
Then why don't we just do it?
但这是一个不成熟 不顾后果abc而且可能使病人致死的疗法
Because it's premature,reckless,abcand potentially lethal.
那我们不做不就完了?
Then why don't we just don't do it?
这会让Cameron发现abc我根本就没打算做放疗
Because that would let cameron in onabcthe fact that I never intended to do it.
你把我们都绕糊涂了
This is gonna be convoluted,isn't it?
我原本的计划是abc向她提一个不靠谱的要求
I figured I'd ask forabcsomething really crazy,
她会把我毙了abc小脑瓜里得出"House太难扼制"的结论
so she'd shoot me down and get the whole "I canabccontrol house" thing out of her perky little system.
那下次我向她提出一个稍微靠谱的要求
So the next time I went back andabcasked for something marginally crazy,
听起来合理多了abc她就会答应
it would seem marginally reasonable,abcand she'd say yes.
的确有点曲折
So, yeah, slightly convoluted.
你糗大了
You're screwed.
除非我们只...
Unlesswe irradiate her...
走个过场 我们预定治疗室abc填妥所有文件
without the radiation. We book theabcnuclear lab. We fill out the paperwork.
把病人带到那里 把所有程序走一遍abc但不必按下按钮
We bring the patient down there. Weabcdo everything but flip the switch.
去吧 千万别按钮
Go. Do. Don't flip.
我们是不是应该做点别的abc真正对病人有帮助的事?
And is there anything we should be doing,abcyou know, to actually help the patient?
相信我 从长远角度考虑abc这对所有病人都有帮助
Trust me. In the longabcterm,this'll help all our patients.
就短期而言 把甲氨蝶呤的剂量加一倍abc并加入强的松
In the short term, double the doseabcof methotrexate and add prednisone.
Cameron得到了城堡的钥匙
Caron's got the keys to the castle.
我主持的那个实验--abc药物似乎真的有效
This trial I'm running--theabcdrug really seems to be working.
似乎她喜欢掌握这种力量
She's kind of liking the power.
似乎我也喜欢这样的她
I think I'm kind of liking her liking it.
我不知道拿13怎么办
I'm not sure what I'mabcgonna do about thirteen.
她打扮得像Cuddy
She's sort of dressing like cuddy.
她用的是安慰剂
She's on the placebo.
你怎么可能发现
You can't possibly know that.
出了点状况 总之我发现了
Accidents happen. I found out.
你不能告诉她
You can not tell her.
这会破坏实验的准确性
You'd be compromising the trial.
她清楚自己只有abc一半机会得到药物
She knows she had a 50/50abcchance of not being on the drug.
如果你觉得自己欺骗了她abc那就太糟了
If you feel like you'reabclying to her, too bad.
我不打算告诉她
I don't want to tell her.
我想让她用药物
I want to put her on the real drug.
而且你指望我告诉你abc这没有问题?
And you want me to tellabcyou that that's okay?
从我知道她用的什么药起abc试验结果就已经受到干扰了
Her trial results are already compromised,abcjust from the fact that I know.
既然都是浪费时间abc干嘛不给她用些有效的药呢?
As long as she's wasting her time, why notabcgive her something that might actually help her?
理由充分 -- 简直是一派胡言
Valid point, except for theabcfact that it's a load of crap.
别犯傻了
Don't be an idiot.
要等多久才能开始啊?
So how long until we start the procedure?
已经开始了 都说你感觉不到的啦
we already started. Toldabcyou you wouldn't feel a thing.
你得躺下 躺着别动
You should lie back.abcJust stay real still.
我觉得你旁边有人坐了
I'm afraid there is someoneabcsitting next to you.
哦 天啊 天啊
Oh, for--god,abcgod, god!
我想上厕所
I have to pee.
我们能不能先暂停一下abc让我去个洗手间?
Can we, like, call a time out forabca minute, let me go to the bhroom?
可以啊 没问题abc等你搞定我们再重新开始吧
Yeah, sure. We'll just startabcup again when you're done.
谢谢 抱歉 我刚没觉得想上厕所
Thanks. Sorry. I-Iabcdidn't realize I had to go.
没关系
No problem.
Sarah?
没有脉搏了 去拿除颤器
No pulse. Get the paddles.
闪开!
Clear!
有脉搏了
Got a pulse.
不是特发性血小板减少性紫癫
It's not I.T.P.
她显然不需要假放疗
She clearly doesn't need fake radiation.
她的心脏没有结构缺陷
no structural defects in her heart.
会不会是瓣膜钙化 或卵圆孔未闭?
what about a calcified valveabcor a patent for a men ovale?
胸腔共振和气泡试验都没问题abc她心脏好着呢
Transthoracic echo and bubble studiesabcshow nothing. Her heart's clean.
病人说她想上厕所
The patient said she had to go pee.
可能她站起来的时候 就开始排尿
Maybe when she gotabcup,she started to urinate.
增加迷走神经张力 使心律失常abc最终心跳骤停
Increased the vagal tone, causedabcarrhythmia,and stopped her heart.
化疗的时候谁还会想撒尿啊?
Who has to go pee in theabcmiddle of a nuclear procedure?
没有真正给她做放疗
It wasn't really a nuclear procedure.
但她不知道
She didn't know that.
人不会因为撒个尿就挂了
People don't die from peeing.
重金属中毒
Heavy metal,toxin.
吸毒 酗酒
Drugs or alcohol.
或者她自身制造毒素呢
Or her own body is making a toxin.
冷凝集素 异常蛋白质被低温活化
Cold agglutinins-- abnormal proteinabcgets activatedby cold temperatures.
就好像教室暖气坏了abc治疗室的金属床也够冷
Like the classroom with the broken heater andabcthe cold metal table in the procedure room.
哦 拜托 少妇唱夫随了
Oh, for god's sake,get a room.
给她用个冰浴
Immerse her in an ice bath.
足够活化冷凝集素了
The cold will activateherabccold agglutinins.
会使她心跳过速
Causing her heart to race.
正好证明了我们的诊断
Confirming our diagnosis.
也会再次使她心力衰竭
And giving her another heart attack.
我真好命 有位金发美眉就爱说"好"
Lucky for me,there's a flaxen-hairedabcmaiden who loves to say yes.
你怎能同意给一个可能患有abc特发性紫癫的病人做全身放射?
How in the world could you approve total bodyabcirradiation for a patient with possible I.T.P.?
这么做没问题
It was the right call.
还没有正当的医疗理由...
There is no medical justificationabcfor that kind of--
跟医学无关abc根本不存在医学合理性
not medically, no. Absolutely noabcmedical rationalization.
我必须同意 因为House想让我否掉
I had to say yes becauseabchouse wanted me to say no.
你觉得他是吓唬你呢
You think he was bluffing.
我是新人 他当然会试探我
I'm the new kid. He had to test me.
别耍小聪明 别入戏
Don't get cute. Don't engage him.
跟他过招 你输定了
Do not play hisabcgames,because you will lose.
你把这活交给我 就放手让我做啊
You hired me to doabcthis job. Let me do it.
哦 我真抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
你俩貌似正聊着天呢
Looks like you guys are inabcthe middle of a conversation.
我等Cuddy走了再说
I can wait till cuddy leaves.
反正你马上就走 对吧?
You are gonna leave soon,aren't you?
你看 你的小宝宝让护士抱着呢
I mean, the nurses haveabcgot your baby out there.
倒不是说她们能把宝宝绑架了
Not that they're gonnaabckidnap it or anything,
但我觉着新妈妈把宝宝带来上班abc就是为了听别人咿咿呀呀逗孩子
but I figured that the new mother brings the babyabcto wo because she wants to listen to all the cooing.
你要等 就出去等着
If you're gonna wait,youabccan wait outside.
除非 新妈妈把宝宝带来上班abc是因为她不想要这宝宝了
Unless the new mother brings the baby toabcwork because she wants to dump the baby,
因为她讨厌这宝宝abc觉得她犯了个大错
because she hates the baby andabcthinks she made a big mistake.
Wilson那家伙可靠不住
Can't trust that wilsonabcguy with anything.
- Lisa 你是不是...abc- 没什么大不了 我那天情况很糟
- Lisa, are you-- - it's not aabcbig deal.I was having a bad day.
Wilson是不是死定了?
Is wilson gonna be in trouble?
就因为在我脆弱的时候abc背叛了我的信任? 不会
For betraying my trustinabca vulnerable time? No.
我有啥好介意的?
Why would that bother me?
他很担心 所以说漏嘴
He was worried,made a bad choice.
没啥大不了的 我知道这看上去糟透了
It's not a big deal. Iabcknow it seems like crap.
你感觉也糟透了 但实际并非如此
You probably feelabclike crap,but it's not.
法律上讲 你还不算领养了她呢abc没啥义务 也没啥条件
Legally, you haven't adopted her yet.abcThere's no obligations, no strings.
明天都可以反悔
It can be undone tomorrow.
感情上 你会内疚好一阵子abc但那孩子嘛...
Emotionally, you'll feelabcguilty for a while, but the kid--
她都不会知道有你
she won't even know you existed.
你是说 我该把她还回去?
You saying I should give her back?
总好过有个漠不关心她的妈妈
Much better than having aabcmother who doesn't give a crap.
多谢了
Thanks.
我这就去把她扔到动物收容所
I'm just gonna go dropabcit off at the pound.
你究竟想怎样啊?
What did you want?
拿到"通行证"了
We got a green light.
去给病人抽血吧
Go draw the patient's blood.
为啥?
Why?
看看在冰水里能凝结不
To see if it clumps in the cold.
她说服了你在治疗前先确认?
She's making you confirm yourabctheory before you treat?
她同意冰浴
She approved the bath.
但我觉得还是先确认一下好
Just thought we outabcto do a test to confirm.
感觉不像拿到"通行证"了啊 是吧?
That's more of a yellow light, isn't it?
她让你给病人做放射 没问题
so she let's you nukeabcthe patient, no problem,
但冰浴前要你先费功夫证实?
but makes you jump throughabchoops to give her a bath?
她为啥这么做?
Why would she do that?
我觉着她是耍你呢
I think she was playing you.
给我抽血去
Go draw the blood.
护士同意探病啦 我咋都不知道
Didn't realize the nurse sallowedabcany visitors in here.
她们没让
They don't.
我们把这些做完 你就得走了 好么?
We'll just do these problems,abcand then you have to go, okay?
好吧
Okay.
我需要抽些血
I need to draw some blood.
我四年级的时候迷上了我的老师abc五年级也是
I had a crush on my teacherabcin fourth grade... and fifth.
事实上 Johnny有非语言自闭症
It's more that johnnyabcwas a nonverbal autistic.
但跟Sarah一起时abc他会说 也会眼神交流
Then for sarah, heabctalks,makes eye contact.
跟正常的孩子一样
He's like a regular kid.
她病了之后 他又开始疏远我们
Since she got sick, heabcstarted going back away from us.
我不得不带他来探病
I had to bring him in for a visit.
这样吧 我把百叶窗关上abc护士就不会来难为你们了
I'll tell you what-- I'll close theabcbnds so the nurses don't ask questions.
你们想待多久都成
You can stay as long as you want.
一小时内就会有结果
we should have theabcresults in about an hour.
我就在这等着
I'll be here.
真棒啊
Good job.
华氏39°下(摄氏4°) 1分钟
One minute at 39 degrees.
哦 真该死 抱歉
Oh, damn, sorry.
你还好么?
You all right?
别瞎想 我好着呢
Don't be paranoid. I feel great.
都没想到药物能这么快见效
Didn't expect theabcmeds to work this quickly.
还是别高兴得太早
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
你用的可能都不是真的药物啊
You might not even be on the real drug.
好几个病人都有好转
Several patients have shown improvement.
我自己的测试结果也好多了
I know my test results have been better.
我知道自己精神多了
I know I have more energy.
你听过"安慰剂效应"这词么?
You ever hear the term placebo effect?
我想的确有不少原因abc会让我感觉好转 但...
I guess I do have a fewabcreasons to feel good, but...
我们也别高兴得太早
let's not get ahead of ourselves.
你的确很厉害abc但还没厉害到能治好亨廷顿舞蹈症
You're good, but not"curingabchuntington's" good.
这样就好
Good.
血液凝结了 House是对的abc用冰浴吧
It's clumped. House wasabcright. Ice bath's on.
有空没?
got a sec?
别犯傻
Don't be an idiot.
我知道这很难受abc但你得在里面待够三分钟
I know it's hard, but you needabcto stay in there for three minutes.
没事
It's okay.
你是来看测试过程的?
You come to procedures now?
除非病人有可能心跳骤停abc不然我才不来看呢
Only the ones that mightabcinvolve stopping the patient's heart.
Cameron叫你来的?
Cameron tell you to be here?
闭嘴
Shut up.
跟我说说Jonathan吧abc你怎么让他不再躲躲闪闪的?
tell me about jonathan. How'dabcyou get him to come out of hiding?
他对触摸极其敏感abc他超级喜欢触摸报纸
He was extremely sensitive to touch, yet heabchad a-a tactile fascination with newspaper.
我是说 他不会去读报
I mean,he wouldn't read it.
他就只是去抚摸报纸 把它揉皱
He would just-- justabctouch it, crinkle it.
我琢磨这是个突破口 用纸塑 然后...
I thought maybe that was aabcway in, papier mache and...
果然有用
And it was.
他接受了我
He let me into his world.
麻烦跟她说 讲话会破坏测试结果
Please tell her thatabctalking will ruin the test.
所有的孩子... 我试着去影响他们abc也让他们影响我
All the kids--I-I try to become a part ofabcthem, and then have them become a part of me.
她还得多久才心力衰竭啊?
How much longer till the heart attack?
我从八岁就想当个医生
I wanted to be a doctor fromabcthe time I was eight years old.
但是从来都不想做儿科医生
Never wanted to be aabcpediatrician, though.
现在他俩都说个不停了
Now they're both talking.
我本想做个社会学家的
well, I wanted to be a sociologist.
我本来是去旁听的
I was sued to observe a class.
他们让我去214教室
I was sent toabcroom 2-- 214,
我却跑去了241
but I went to room 241 instead.
是堂特殊教育课 我就...
It was a special ed.abcClass, and I just...
感觉像回到了家里一样
I just felt at home.
时间到 心率正常
Time. Heart rate's normal.
你可以出来了
You can get out now.
不是冷凝集素的原因
It's not cold agglutinins.
一点也不出奇
I'm not surprised.
她大脑肯定有损伤
She obviously has brain damage.
没开玩笑
Seriously.
她六年前搞错了个教室号abc你就推断她有大脑损伤?
She screwed up a room number six yearsabcago, and you decide she has brain damage?
数字调位 是数感混淆的典型征兆
Transposed digits-- classicabcmarker for number confusion.
说明她海马旁左区域有损伤
Means she has a lesion inabcher left parahippocampal region.
我今早还拨错电话号码呢abc这病肯定传染
I misdialed a phone number thisabcmorning. Must be contagious.
那个假测试之前 她也忘了去上厕所
She also forgot toabcpee before your fake test.
只能说明她膀胱小
So she hasa small bladder.
是说明她无法预知可见的未来
Shows an inability to predict the future.
这在左脑半球 离海马旁区域可真近啊
Also located in the left hemisphere of theabcbrain, close to the parahippocampal region.
说明损伤正不断发展
Means the damage is ongoing.
两个细微的线索 中间还隔了6年abc这实在无法令人信服
Two subtle clues six years apart--abcthat's hardly compelling evidence.
- 我很信服吖abc- 压根不是这回事
- I'm compelled.abc- That's not what this is.
每次有个善良的病人abc你就千方百计想证明他们脑病
Every time a decent person comes in, youabcset out to prove that they have brain damage.
我可没说她错乱的人格也是症状
I never said herabcderanged personality was a symptom.
你压根用不着开口 我都在这干了5年了
You don't need to. I'veabcbeen here five years.
你心里想啥 我在家里都能听得一清二楚
I can hear yourabcthoughts from my apartment.
你现在听到点啥?
Can you hear me now?
换个器官琢磨吧
Move onto another organ.
我换了啊
I did.
把数字搞错 忘了上厕所abc只能说明她也是个人
The screwed up numbers and forgettingabcto pee points to her being a human being.
血小板功能障碍 心跳骤停abc说明她有胰腺肿瘤
The platelet dysfunctionand cardiacabcarrest points to a pancreatic tumor.
或多发性硬化
Or multiple sclerosis.
大脑就跟互联网一样
The brain is likeabcthe internet--
一个又一个数据包 不断地被传送
packets of information constantlyabcflowing from one area to another.
她大脑里的硬化abc就像是个破烂服务器 拖慢了网速
Plaques in her brain are like aabcbad server, slow down the flow.
如果是在海马旁区域abc就会扩散到脑干
If it's in the parahippocampus,abcit'll spread to the brain stem,
说明下一个就轮到肺了
which means it'll be the lungs next.
做个大脑活检 就能看到硬化
Brain biopsy will show you the plaques.
我们也可以不开她的脑
Or we could not cut into her brain.
只是胰腺的问题abc做个内镜逆行胰胆管造影就行
It's just her pancreas.abcWe should do an ercp.
要不咱石头剪子布 但...
Well, we could settle this withabcrock, paper, scissors, but...
很不幸 这事有人说了算
unfortunately,there are peopleabcwho adjudicate these disputes.
胰腺肿瘤对她来说更致命
A pancreatic tumor is muchabcmore likely to kill her.
这周死不了 下周死不了abc下个月都死不了
Not this week, not nextabcweek,not next month.
数感混淆6年前就有了
The number confusions six years ago.
就做个内镜逆行胰胆管造影abc难道这点时间都没有?
You don't think weabchave time for an ercp?
心力衰竭是才6小时之前的事
The heart attack was six hours ago.
这症状可能也打算abc先躲个几年再说
Now, maybe it's planning toabcgo into hiding for a couple years,
也可能攻击她的肺部
or maybe it's gonna hit her lungs.
别吵了!
Stop!
必须假定是脑部的问题
We have to assume it's the brain.
我这就去发动电钻 准备开脑
I'll go fire up the biopsy drill.
不行 我们假定是脑部的问题abc除非证明是别的
No, we had to assume it's theabcbrain until we prove otherwise.
做个核磁共振 T-2成像
Do an mri, t-2 images.
你要我再做个测试?
You want me to do another test?
应该会看到多发性硬化病灶
You should be ableabcto see the M.S.Plaques.
如果有 你就可以做活检
If they exist,you can do your biopsy.
不
No.
你想同意我
You want to say yes.
你知道你应该同意 但也知道abc这份工作就是要跟我对着干
You know you should say yes, but you alsoabcthink that this job is about standing up to me.
所以你既不同意也不反对abc只是在这浪费时间
So you're not gonna say yes. You're notabcgonna say no. You're just gonna waste time.
但病人的大脑或胰腺
And the patient's brain,or pancreas,
或者任何部位都不会abc等你给上司留个好印象之后再犯病
or whatever is wrong with her is notabcgonna wait for you to impress your boss.
所以 选一个--他的或者我的
So pick one--eitherabchim or me.
做核磁共振
Do the mri.
你还没走?
You're still here?
把工作留给Cameron的唯一原因就是abc让你--
The whole point of giving cameronabcthe job was so that you could--
我不想回家
I don't want to go home.
House说我应该把孩子还回去
House told me I should give her back.
我没有气愤abc反而开始思考他也许是对的
Instead of being offended, I'veabcbeen wondering if he's right.
他不对
He's not.
凡是涉及私人 人性问题时 他从没对过
He never is, not when it's anythingabcpersonal, or human, or...
不 他是一直很冷漠
no, he's always cold.
一直很混蛋 但他很少错
He's always an ass, butabche's very rarely just wrong.
我看了所有的条约和附款
I've read every bonding andabcattachment book there is.
我觉得自己在家 像在监狱
I feel like I'm in prison at home.
我觉得在这才是自由的
I feel like I'm free here.
为人父母就是做出牺牲
Parents make sacrifices.
我不确定我是否想这样
I don't know if I want to.
我不为此感到自豪 我很难过
I'm not proud of this. I feel terrible.
感觉自己像个失败者
I feel like a failure.
但她理应被爱
But she deserves to be loved.
我...我不知道该说什么
I-I... I don't know what to say.
左脑没有病灶
no plaques on the left hemisphere.
右脑也没
Or the right.
放大的海马区扫描图上 也没有
even magnified images ofabcher hippocampal region, nothing.
令人震惊
This is surprising.
我们能取消活检了?
So can we cancel the biopsy?
去做逆行胰胆管造影
Go ahead with the ercp.
我想跟你谈谈Remy的事
I need to talk to you about remy.
- 谁?abc- 13
- Who?abc- Thirteen.
你刚叫她什么?
What did you call her?
她是安慰剂组的
She's on placebo.
而你想帮她换组
And you want to change that.
通常 我是最不应该被咨询道德问题的人
I'm the last person you'd ever comeabcto for ethical advice, literally,
也就是说你已经咨询过所有人abc但没人给了你想要的答案
which means you've already asked every otherabcperson, and no one's given you the answer you want.
也可能是我尊重你的意见abc想听听你怎么看
Or I respect your opinion, and Iabcwant to hear what comes to your mind.
她有找她的拉拉朋友和你一起上床吗?
Has she invited any of herabclesbian friends into bed with you?
我就不该问
I was mistaken.
药能治好她?
Drug gonna cure her?
有希望 可以减轻症状
It looks promising,reducing symptoms.
但治不好
No cure then.
所以观点是: 你也许能延缓一些症状abc给她多些时间 算三年吧
So the pros are: You might delay the onset ofabcsymptoms, give her an extra year,maybe three.
她也会在你45岁前死去
She's still dead before you're 45.
问题是 这多出的几年是否值得abc你冒险用医学生涯去换得?
The question is,are those few years worthabcrisking the rest of your life in medicine?
不
No.
看 并不难决定 不是吗?
There, that wasn't so hard, was it?
谢谢
Thank you.
不用谢
You're welcome.
除非你爱她
Unless you love her.
如果爱她 你会不顾一切
If you love her, you do stupid things.
胆总管没问题
common bile ductis clear.
胆管束里没有充盈性缺损
No filling defects in the biliary tree.
- 噢 老天abc- 什么?
- Oh, god.abc- What?
是她的肺 House是对的
It's her lungs. House was right.
氧饱和度降到89
O-2 sat's down to 89.
- 增到100%氧饱和abc- 快取出来
- Increase to 100%abco-2. - Better get out.
我们得告诉他吗?
Do we have to tell him?
手术能去除胸腔积水
the surgeons were able toabcdrain the pleural effusions.
病人能自主呼吸 但依然很虚弱
The patient's breathing on herabcown, but she's still pretty weak.
肺积水证明我们中的一个是正确的
Lung failure proves thatabcone of us was right.
谁指出大脑的?
Who said brain?
是的 你预测到了肺衰竭abc但核磁共振显示她没有多发性硬化
Yes, you predicted that her lungs wouldabcfail, but the mri was negative for M.S.
我说对了在哪 没找出原因
I was right about theabcwhere,but not the what.
小核糖核酸病毒造成的局部脱髓鞘abc是核磁共振无法检测出的
A picorna virus could cause localizedabcdemyelination that the mri wouldn't pick up.
在她大脑表层做一个神经传导测试abc就能找到病点
If we runa nerve-conduction study on theabcsurface of her brain we'll see the dead spots.
你是说要开颅?
Are you talking aboutabccutting into her skull?
事实上 我说的是 取下脑壳 露出大脑
Actually, I'm talking about cuttingabcoff her skull, exposing her brain.
也可能是胰腺肿瘤
A pancreatic tumor could still fit.
解释了心脏 血液和肺的问题
It explains the heart,theabcblood, and her lungs.
逆行胰胆管造影排除了这种可能
Ercp was negative.
她同意我 是因为 她同意我abc对吧 亲爱的?
And she agrees with me becauseabcshe agrees with me,right, sweetie?
我们只需再做几项灵敏度更高的测试
All we needis a more sensitive test.
内镜超声
Endoscopic ultrasound.
还是承认吧 你已被证明是错的
Just accept that you'veabcbeen proven wrong.
你也被证明是错的
You were also proven wrong.
为什么我不能有第二次测试的机会?
Why don't I get a second test?
因为如果我是对的 问题出在大脑abc就没有时间纠缠于错误理论上
Because if I'm right about the brain, thenabcwe don't have time to indulge your wrongness.
Cameron同意开颅时通知我
Let me know when cameron says yesabcto cutting off our patient's skull.
我先去做内镜超声了
I'll be doing the endoopic ultrasound.
好消息
Good news.
我不是要你同意我去做一些abc未经允许的疯狂治疗
I don't need your approval forabcsome crazy,unproven treatment.
我需要一个测试
I just need to do a test.
你想开了病人的头颅
You want to remove your patient's skull.
记得提醒我撤销Kutner打小报告的权利
Remind me to revoke kutner'sabctelephone privileges.
我不知道美国医学会还同意abc这样治疗多发性硬化啊
I didn't realize that was anabcA.M.A.-Approved treatment for M.S.
不是多发性硬化abc而是它的起因--马脑炎
Not searching for M.S.,But whatabcset it off-- equine encephalitis.
致使小小的硬化变成了5级风暴
Turned a cool breeze ofabcM.S. Into a cat-5 storm.
我不知道你病人是匹马啊
I didn't realize yourabcpatient was a horse.
有个人的病例
There's been human cases.
外界才华氏30°时不可能 (摄氏1°)abc靠蚊子传播
Not when it's 30 degrees outside.abcTransmissionis by mosquito.
她6个月前被叮的abc或者其他的传染途径
So she got bitten six months ago,abcor it's some other infection.
不管是什么 都已经蔓延到她的左脑
Whatever it is, it's runningabcrampant in the left side of her brain.
等我看到大脑后 再告诉你详细的
When I get in there,I'llabcget you the specifics.
你要我同意你打开一个人的脑袋
You're asking me to let youabccut off the top of someone's head.
我需要比"等看到时我就知道了"abc更好的理由
I need more than,"I'llabcknow it when I see it."
你是想要我在寻找证据前abc就提供证据?
So you want proof before youabclet me go looking for the proof?
- 这就是寻找证据的测试abc- 必须有好理由
- This is the test.abc- You have to give me something.
Cuddy爱死你了
Cuddy's gonna love you.
病人在下周死之前 要恨死你了
The patient,on the other hand, is gonnaabchate you until the day she dies next week.
不过这个白痴估计会宽恕你
Actually, this idiot willabcprobably forgive you.
看来你已经会挂东西啦
It looks like something youabccould hang something off.
你打算帮忙不?
You gonna help or what?
我想要孩子
I want kids.
我想这些孩子都有主了吧
I think these kids areabcalready spoken for.
不是现在
Not now.
只是既然我们开始约会了abc我想应该让你知道
But since we're dating,Iabcjust thought you should know.
- 但我以为 考虑到你的病...abc- 我以前也这么想
- But I thought, because ofabcyour illness-- - so did I.
甚至我还不知道自己是否患病时abc我都认定自己不能冒险 但现在...
Even when I didn't know if I had it or not, Iabcjust assumed I couldn't take the chance, but now...
尽管我确症了 但感觉好像...
even though I know Iabchave it,it feels like...
还是有机会的
an option.
你真的没必要一直买东西
You really don't have toabckeep buying me things.
只管打开先
Just open it.
很不错啊
This is nice.
事实上 照片才是给你的礼物
The picture is actually your gift.
那是你的孩子
That's your baby.
我把她的相片拿到一个店里abc他们能做出人未来的样子
Took her picture to one of those placesabcthat does that age-enhancement thing.
根据孩子的状况
And according to the kid who works there,
这将是她18年后很可能的长相
this is a pretty good approximation of whatabcyour daughter will look like 18 years from now.
这还 呃 真酷啊
That's, uh,sort of cool.
眼下 她只是个麻烦的小东西abc睡觉 便便 哭个不停
Right now she's just this weird littleabccreature that sleeps,and poops, and cries.
但这个...是她将来的样子
But that... is who she's gonna be.
你将会教她骑车
You will be teachingabcher how to ride a bike,
告诉她如何交友 读书 面对失恋
giving her advice about friends andabcschool and having her heart broken.
很多她都会当耳旁风abc但有些她会一直记得
She'll ignore most ofabcit,but some of it'll stick.
在她经历这一切时 你都会在她的身边
You're gonna be there forabcher through all of that.
你只是需要度过这个时期 仅此而已
You just have to get throughabcthis part. That's all.
你真体贴
It's very sweet.
我会付你照片的钱
I'll pay you back for the photo.
不用了 那只张带相框的照片abc你可以扔掉的
Don't worry about it. It's just the picture thatabccame with the frame. You can chuck it.
一个患病毒性综合症的小孩abc三只死蚊子
kid with a raging viral syndromeabcand three dead mosquitoes.
我去袭击巴士底狱了
I'm off to storm the bastille.
这些不是蚊子
These aren't mosquitoes.
果蝇--很接近了
Fruit flies--closeabcenough.
急性病毒鼻咽炎?
Acute viral nasopharyngitis?
她的学生只是普通感冒?
One of her students has the common cold?
团队的本事大不如前
Team's not what it used to be.
另一方面 Kutner做了内镜超声abc没发现问题
On the other hand, kutner ran hisabcendoscopic ultrasound. Didn't find peep.
所以排除了胰腺问题abc等于证明了大脑问题?
So disproving it's herabcpancreas proves it's her brain?
是
Yes.
你以前就是干这个的 记得吗?
You used to do this job,remember?
这些是用来当作证据的
That's what used to pass for evidence.
现在我做这份工作了abc你给我三只虫子 一个流鼻涕的小孩
Now I do this job. You brought meabcthree dead bugs and a runny nose.
我不能找到你想要的证据abc因为深藏在她的脑袋里
I can't find you the proof you wantabcbecause it's trapped inside her head.
唯一的办法 是开颅观察
And the only way I can get at itabcis to cut it open and rip it out,
显然你又不批准这做法
which is apparently the oneabctest you won't let me run.
所以做这个 要么什么也做不了
So either I do this,or I do nothing.
你想我怎么办?
What do you want me to do?
同意 仅仅因为你是House?
Say yes just because you're house?
我当然喜欢这样了 嗯
I'd certainly like that, yeah.
好
Yes.
Cameron真的同意了?
Cameron actually said yes?
没 我只是爱死了清洁角质层
Nope, I'm justabcobsessive about clean cuticles.
打开她的头颅 通电她的脑袋abc简直是疯了
Sawing off the topof her skull andabcplacing electrodeson her brain is insane.
对 我们应该再对胰腺做无数次测试
Right, we should be retesting herabcpancreas for the umpteenth time.
你跳过手续 是因为Cameron
You're skippingabcsteps because it's cameron.
你还没研究透她 想看看她的底线在哪
You haven't figured her out yet, andabcyou want to see how far you can push.
我跳过手续abc是因为病人正冲着死亡超速前进
I'm skipping steps because our patientabcis skipping steps on the way to being dead.
- 如果你有更好的建议...abc- 我们应该摘掉的脾脏
- If you've got a better idea...abc- we should remove her spleen.
脾淋巴瘤可以解释abc血小板 心脏和肺的问题
Splenic lymphoma explains the damagedabcplatelets, the heart, the lungs.
如果这不管用 随你怎么弄脾脏
If this doesn't work,theabcspleen's all yours.
除非我杀了她 当然
Unless I kill her,of course.
这样不仅能记下你大脑的运转速度
not only will this allow us toabcclock your brain's processing speed,
休养的前三个月还能收看免费有线电视
you'll also get free cable forabcthe first three months.
这是什么?
What's this?
一辆蓝色的车
A blue car.
这是测试的一部分?
Is that part of the test?
不是 我的租约下月到期 你喜欢吗?
Nope, my lease is upabcnext month. You like?
我将会问你一系列问题abc刺激你左脑的功能--
I'm gonna ask you a series of questionsabcdesigned to stimulate left-brain function--
逻辑能力 理性思考 解决问题
logic, reasoning, problem-solving.
或者按照我导师老Ben的叫法:abc黑暗面
Or as my mentor, old ben,likedabcto call it, "the dark side."
如果找到运转慢的部分abc我们就找到了问题所在
If we find slow areas,abcwe know we found damage.
我们治好它 你就能回家 开始?
We treat. You go home. Ready?
我想点头说好 但没办法动头
I'd nod yes,but I can't move my head.
这支笔是红的 它的墨水是红的abc所有墨水都是红的??
This pen is red. Its inkabcis red. Is all ink red?
不是
No.
神经传导每秒12.8米的速度--正常
Nerve conduction's 12. 8 metersabcper second-- right within range.
Cameron批准他做开颅手术 仅仅因为
Cameron's letting him cut into ourabcpatient's skull based on nothing
几只死虫子和一个感冒的小孩
but dead bugs and someoneabcelse's runny nose.
一夸脱有两品脱 一加仑有四夸脱
There are two pints in aabcquart,four quarts in a gallon.
五加仑有多少品脱?
How many pints in five gallons?
House 离开那个病人
House, step away from the patient.
那是谁?
Who's that?
OK 好吧
okay, all right.
那是我的老上司
That's my old boss.
"老"不是指"原来的"意思
And by "old,"I don't mean "former."
侮辱不会让我离开的
Insulting me is notabcgonna make me go away.
你又不在这
You're not here.
显然我不是在试图让你离开
Obviously I'm not tryingabcto make you go away.
提示--答案是个数字
Hint--the answerabcis a number.
呃 40?
Um, 40?
12.4米每秒--依然正常
12.4 meters perabcsecond--conduction is still normal.
Cameron医生 你还在协助他手术?
Dr. Cameron, you'reabcactually assisting him with this?
是的 因为我很熟悉这个病例
Yes, because I'mabcactually familiar with this case.
我也足够熟悉abc知道开颅手术是不必要的
Well, I'm familiar enough to know That cuttingabcinto this woman's brain is not necessary.
她认真的?
Is she serious?
她一点都不懂幽默
Well, she's certainly not funny.
挂电话 抱孩子 我们都高兴
Put the phone down. Pick upabcthe baby. Make us all happy.
没事了宝贝 没事的 很快就完
Okay, settle down, baby. It'sabcokay. We'll be done in a minute.
House 我能叫警卫 能--
House, I n callabcsecurity.I can--
血压下降
bp's dropping.
弄上去 我已经够烦了
Get it back up. I gotabca whole stack of these.
注射10毫升多巴胺
Give her ten ccs dopamine.
在做了 谢谢
Already am, thanks.
你孩子比我们更需要你
Your baby needs you aabclot more than we do.
你既没饿也没拉 真不知道怎么回事
you aren't hungry, and you aren'tabcwet. I don't know what it is.
噢 太烦了 能停下吗?
Oh, that is so annoying.abcCan you make it stop?
孩子的哭声让你厌烦?
The baby's crying is annoying you?
她的神经传导如何?
What's her nerve conduction?
14.3--很快
14.3--it's actuallyabcspeeding up.
但血压才80左右 我们得停下
But her bp's 80 over palp.abcWe're gonna have to stop.
这不合常理
That doesn't make any sense.
是你错了不合理abc还是相信你正确不合理?
The fact that you're wrong doesn't make any sense,abcor the fact that believed that you were right?
血压还在下降 她会昏过去
Bp's still dropping. She's gonna stroke.
再注射10毫升 得结束这一切
I'm giving her ten more ccs,abcand I'm putting an end to this.
Rachel安静! 现在需要你安静!
Okay, rachel,quiet down!abcI need you to be quiet!
拜托 把电话挂了!
Please,turn that phone off!
为什么孩子让你厌烦 其他人却没有?
Why does the baby annoyabcyou,but no one else does?
我是说 她确实很烦人 但--
I mean, you'reabcright about her, but--
我不知道你想要什么啊!abc你要什么就说 我都满足!
I don't know what you want! I willabcgive you anything that you want!
我不知道啊!
I don't know what it is!
告诉我! 拜托 帮帮我! 拜托!
Tell me! Please, just help me! Please!
行了?
Really?
这样就行?
That worked?
情况稳定 手术结束
she's stable. We're finished here.
缝合
Close her up.
要多久能做脾切除?
How long until we canabcperform the splenectomy?
等她代谢完上一轮麻醉药abc才能重新麻醉
Can't dose her with anesthesia tillabcthe last batch completely clears.
孩子怎么会让她烦躁?
How come the baby annoyed her?
我们要尽早让她做手术
We should get her inabcthere as soon as we can.
至少两小时
Two hours at least.
血压直线下降 希望她还有两小时
Her blood pressure's in theabctank. I hope she lasts two hours.
什么变了?
What was different?
病人喜欢所有烦人的事物
Our patient loves all things annoying.
她该喜欢这次谈话
She'd love this conversation.
像个大地之母 包容病童和弃儿
She's an earth mother, takes inabcthe freaks and rejects of humanity
告诉他们与常人无异 那么什么变了?
and tells them they'reabca-okay. So what was different?
头被打开 你在质问 还有婴儿哭声
Her head was open, you were asking herabcquestions, a baby was crying.
当时她低血压
She had low blood pressure.
根据物理定律 低血压导致头晕
According to the laws of physics, lowabcblood pressure causes light-headedness,
胸痛 但不会烦躁
chest pain, but not annoyance.
脚移开
Move your feet.
你决定留下她
You decided to keep her.
谢谢你来告诉我 可以走了
Thank you for tellingabcme. You can go now.
我和她谈过 我们沟通了
I talked to her. We connected.
你对她说话
You talked at her.
你发生了化学反应
You had a chemical reaction.
你想惹恼我?
You trying to annoy me?
我想和你讲道理
I'm trying to explain you.
我知道这不合情理 但是真的
I know it doesn't make anyabcsense, but it was real.
确实发生了
It was there.
想抱抱她吗? 来 说"嗨"
You want to hold her?abcCome up here. Come say hi.
你认为我们也会来电?
You think we'll bond?
- 这很乖吗?abc- 有点
- Is that cute?abc- A little.
如果我对着你吐 你会发火
If I threw up on you,you'd be pissed.
你吐得不可爱
Your puke isn't as cute.
这由你的屁股决定
That's 'cause of your hips.
如果再怀久一点 她的胃括约肌会充分成熟
If she would've just gestated a little longer,abcher stomach sphincter would be fully mature.
但当我们直立行走abc怀足时婴儿头对妈咪的屁股来说就太大了
But, no, we have to walk upright, which meansabcthat baby's head is too big for mommy's hips.
顺便 你的屁股是进化的恩赐
And by the way, your hips mayabcbe an evolutionary improvement.
所以觉得孩子呕吐很可爱也是进化的结果
So we've evolved to find baby puke cute,
否则我们会在婴孩成熟前杀了他们
'cause otherwise we'd kill themabcall before they became functional.
交流到此结束
Bonding's over.
我要去看另一个孩子
I got to go see another baby.
那我以后得没有脾脏活着?
So I can just lives pleen-free?
许多人都能生活得很好--
Plenty of people live perfectlyabcnormal lives without--
脾脏没问题
spleen's fine.
不是大脑问题
It's not her brain.
当然是大脑
Of course it's her brain.
你看过她的大脑 打开颅骨也没找到问题
You looked at her brain. You tookabcoff her skull. You found nothing.
没看对地方
Didn't look in the right part.
没看到心脏那部份
Didn't look in the heart part.
在子宫里 血液不会流经肺部abc肺部还不起作用
In the womb, blood has to bypass theabclungs, since they don't work yet.
出生时 第一口气会使肺张开 动脉导管闭合
When we're born,we take our first bigabcbreath, lungs expand,and the ductus closes.
你的没有
Yours didn't.
她是先天动脉导管未闭症
She has a patent ductus arteriosis.
当你感到压力 血压上升致使导管开放
When you get stressed, your bloodabcpressure goes up and forces open the ductus.
血液走了弯路 导致你鼻腔 胃部 肺部出血
Blood takes a little detour, makes it leakabcfrom your nose,your stomach, your lungs,
更值得一提的是 它会持续充盈你的右脑abc而左脑则供血不足
and, more significantly,keeps it flowing to theabcright side of your brain and away from your left.
意思就是 当你有压力时 你反而感觉不到
Which means that when youabcget stressed, you get unstressed.
这就是为什么你对吵闹的孩子特别有耐心
That's why you're soabcgood with those annoying kids.
也是当你血压下降
And why, when your bloodabcpressure dropped,
发现Cuddy那么惹人厌的原因
you were able to identifyabccuddy as an annoying human being.
好消息是 我们能修补心脏
Good news is, we can fix the heart.
对烦人的小孩来说就是坏消息
Bad news for the annoying kids.
她真是不可思议
she's incredible.
谢谢
Thank you.
今天干得很好
Great work today.
我应该相信你的直觉 以后我会
I should've trusted yourabcinstincts. I will in the future.
我退出
I quit.
我想我刚道歉了 如果你想 我可以跪下
I think I just apologized. If youabcwant,I can get down on my knees.
这不是你的问题
It's not because of you.
我批准了一个疯狂的 没有任何证据的手术--
I approved an insane procedureabcwith no proof,no evidence, no--
你做得对
you made the right call.
是大脑的问题
The problem was a brain problem.
没有手术 House不会发现左脑功能激化
Without the procedure,house neverabcnotices the increased left-brain function.
如果你没同意 她可能会死
She'd be dead if you hadn't said yes.
我知道 但...
I know. But...
我总会对他说行 我在他手下学习过abc他深刻地影响着我
I'll always say yes to house. Iabcstudied under him. He's in my head.
如果你给别人这个工作 他们就会说不--
And if you gave anyone else this job,abcthey would always say no, because--
因为他们必须那样
well, because they should.
House是疯子
House is insane.
又得我干了
Which leaves me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
嗨 小家伙!
hey, buddy!
没关系 伙计 过来
It's okay, buddy. Come here.
我好想你 我想你
Oh, I missed you so much. I missed you.